Sometimes this question comes in the customer's mind
that what will happen to his policy when it
comes in the market, then he has to deposit at
least Rs 100 crore with IRDA, the regulatory body of insurance company of India.
So not every company gets the license so easily.
First of all, they have to pay
Rs 100 crore for the license.
Secondly, every company has to maintain a solvency ratio
which is minimum
that if the company has taken a premium of Rs 100 from the customer, then it should be able to
pay back the customer at
all times. So, we
can see what is the solvency of every company.
For example, Aditya Birla has 1.8, that is,
Rs 1. If they have taken Rs 1 as premium from the customer, then
Aditya Birla has Rs 180 to pay back to the customer.
Similarly, you will see that Ego has 0
points, the
third company has 3.40. If you
look, Bajaj has 6.86, sorry, 6.6 for Rs 1.  There is
₹6 in front, in the same way
you can see every company including LIC. The
next point, if I tell you, every
insurance company,
even the private companies in the market, all those companies have to
tie up with a foreign company,
which are almost 100 years old
companies, which have a long experience in the global market all over the world. For example, if you
look at HDFC,
they have a joint venture with a Mauritius company,
Max Life has a
joint venture with a Japanese company, ICICI has a
UK company, their joint venture is
with Kotak, a South African company,
Birla Sun Life has a
joint venture with a Canadian company, Tata has an
American company called American
International Assurance, that company has a
tie up with SBI, a French
company, so every company has a
joint venture with a foreign company,
which has a very long experience in doing insurance business all over the world. Let us
try to understand you by taking an example
like with Tata.  I am a joint venture company of the company.
This company was
established in 1919. It
is a 130-year-old company.
If you look at its value, it is
around 22 lakh crores. 22 lakh crores is
written here, which is 20084 billion dollars.
If you convert this into Indian rupees, it will be
22 lakh crores. So, this is such an
old company. Similarly, all the other
companies which have joint ventures are
very big companies and very
old companies. We talked about 100 crore
security, we talked about Solanki, we talked about
our joint venture company.
Now let's talk about the insurance company.
Whenever an insurance company provides insurance cover of 20 lakhs or more, then it is
insured by the insurance company. That means the insurance
company also gets it insured. Okay, suppose there is
a customer named X who has
taken a term insurance plan of 5000000
from XX Company. XX Company will also
go and insure him for 50 lakhs from the insurance company. So,
if something happens to XX,
remember?  If something happens to the customer, the
excise company gives it money and
that company goes and
takes the money back from the insurance company. So let me
tell you one more important thing,
if you notice here, in India,
including LIC, on the
side of which it is written
23 Life Insurance Complete Including D
Insurance LIC,
okay, then LIC also provides insurance,
you can see this in the next news, in details,
I have explained this in the Mint news that has come,
and if you want to
understand this, then let me tell you, on 23 November 2022,
LIC's term plan,
New Jeevan Hamara, was launched, why did it have to be launched?
Because the insurance company had refused to insure them at the old rate,
so they had to increase the premium of the insurance,
which is 35 to 40%. The premium in this plan is 100%. According to the
rules in India, an
insurance company cannot be closed now, it will have to be
merged with some other company. It did
not do business properly in India
or it was not in profit, so
whom did they send their business to?
Exide Life ran it for some time.  Now,
a year ago, there is news that their
business is also not running well, so they have also
merged their business
with HDFC Life. So, the customer who has taken an Ing
Life Insurance policy will
now get HDFC Life Insurance, which means
his money is safe and is not going to go anywhere. So,
if I summarize, you
can take a policy from any of the 24 insurance companies.
All the companies are safe.
All the companies are good companies, but the
products may be different, the premiums may be
different,
you should check them and then purchase. Companies
will not close down, due to this you will never suffer any loss.
Thank you so much.
To subscribe to the channel, you can go to YouTube and
in the search button of YouTube, go to Anil
Rajbhar Triple FS Family First
Financial Services, there my
picture will appear. By
clicking on the video, you
can also watch all my other videos which will
help you a lot. Please like, subscribe,
share and thank you.